Larry D. Thomas, II

Data Scientist | Psychometrician

San Francisco, CA

708.935.2563 | <u>LThomas2@gmail.com</u> github.com/ldt2 linkedin.com/in/larry-d-thomas

Data Scientist with a background in psychometrics, applied linguistics, and educational research. Quantitative researcher with 8 years of experience in designing and analyzing both quantitative and qualitative research studies with an emphasis on people research.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Statistics: linear and non-linear mixed effects regression models; Bayesian inference; data visualization **Machine Learning**: clustering; classification methods; regression modeling; graphical models **Causal Inference**: experimental and quasi-experimental design; propensity score analysis and matching **Psychometrics**: multidimensional item response theory; factor analysis; latent class analysis **Software and Programming**: R; SAS; Python; SQL

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Science Immersive

Galvanize

January 2019 – April 2019

Los Angeles, CA, USA

• 3-month, 700+ hour data science immersive training program covering core data science areas and skills including probability and statistics, databases, machine learning algorithms, and data visualization. Main technologies used: Python, SQL, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, MongoDB.

Measurement Research Associate

February 2016 - January 2019

STEM Program - WestEd

Redwood City, CA, USA

- Designed and implemented quantitative and qualitative research studies for educational technology startups to evaluate the efficacy of new products and to inform product development decisions
- Created psychometric analysis plan for the development and analysis of a large-scale assessments and simulation- and games-based assessments
- Developed program-wide data collection and analysis protocols with accompanying codebase repositories
- Disseminated research and evaluation findings to technical and non-technical audiences through technical reports, executive summaries, marketing reports, research articles, conference presentation

Graduate Student Researcher

October 2008 - March 2016

National Center for Research on Evaluation, Standards and Student Testing

Los Angeles, CA, USA

- Constructed measures of drug abuse recovery using multidimensional item response theory
- Provided methodological and statistical expertise to graduate students and faculty
- Used multilevel propensity score matching techniques to create matched treatment and control samples to draw causal inferences for a state-wide evaluation of after school programs
- Performed psychometric analyses to evaluate the validity and reliability of assessments of content specific reading strategies

EDUCATION

University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA, USA Ph.D. in Advanced Quantitative Methodology, In-progress (ABD)

University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA, USA M.A. in Advanced Quantitative Methodology, 2009

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA, USA

B.A. in Spanish (Hispanic Studies), 2005

Instituto Tecnológico y de Estudios Superiores de Monterrey (ITESM), Guadalajara, Jalisco, México

Study Abroad, Summer 2002; 2003 –2004

Areas of Study: Spanish Linguistics and Mathematics